A Finding Aid to the Ben Benn Papers, 1905-1993, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bennben
Archives of American Art
Ben Benn papers
1905-1993
AAA.bennben
Archives of American Art
6.3 Linear feet
The papers of modernist painter Ben Benn measure 6.3 linear feet and date from 1906 through 1977, with the bulk of the papers dating from circa 1920 - circa 1970. The collection includes correspondence between Benn and his wife Velida Benn and letters from Oscar Bluemner, Max Weber, Joseph Stella, and other artists. Also found are sketches, sketchbooks, diaries, scrapbooks, personal business records, clippings, photographs, exhibition catalogs, art journals, and auction catalogs. Some of the printed material is quite rare.
Benn, Ben, 1884-
Biographical Note
New York painter Ben Benn was born in Russia in 1884 as Benjamin Rosenberg and died in 1983. Benn studied drawing and painting at the National Academy of Design from 1904-1908 and had his first exhibition, "Oils by Eight American Artists," at the Artists' Gallery in 1907. In 1916, Benn participated in the "Forum Exhibition of Modern American Painters" at the Anderson Galleries, along with artists Thomas Hart Benton, Oscar Bluemner, Arthur Dove, Marsden Hartley, John Marin, Man Ray, Abraham Walkowitz, and others. The exhibition was important in advancing the cause of modern art in American, particularly the American avant-garde and was recreated by the Whitney in 1983.
Best known as a modern painter who assimilated in his early style the influences of Matisse, Picasso, and Kandinsky, Benn's first one-man show was held at the J. B. Neumann Gallery in 1925. Portraits, still-lifes, and landscapes formed the core of Benn's subject themes and he often shifted between abstract and figurative images. He is known for his strong joyful colors, thick brush strokes and energetic paintings.
Benn was featured in over twenty one-man exhibitions and countless group shows. Major exhibitions included Abstract Painting in America (Whitney Museum, 1935), American Painting Today (Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1950), and Ben Benn, Painter (The Jewish Museum, 1965). The Smithsonian's Hirshhorn Museum in Washington, D.C. honored Benn with a one-man show on his ninetieth birthday (1974). His work is in permanent museum collections in both the U.S. and abroad including the Albany Institute of Art, the Smithsonian Institution's Hirshhorn Museum, the Knoxville Art Center, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Newark Museum, Whitney Museum of American Art, as well as the Museum of Arts, Ein-Harod in Israel and the Kröller-Müller Museum in Holland.
Ben Benn was a recipient of several awards for his achievement in painting. The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts honored Benn with the Henry Schiedt award (1952) and the Carol Beck Gold Medal (1965); Benn was also the recipient of the Knoxville Art Center Purchase Prize in 1961. In 1970 Benn was a beneficiary of the Childe Hassam Fund awarded through the American Academy of Arts and Letters.
Benn's work is in permanent museum collections in both the U.S. and abroad including the Albany Institute of Art, the Smithsonian Institution's Hirshhorn Museum, the Knoxville Art Center, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Newark Museum, Whitney Museum of American Art, as well as the Museum of Arts, Ein-Harod in Israel and the Kröller-Müller Museum in Holland.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of modernist painter Ben Benn measure 6.3 linear feet and date from 1906 through 1977, with the bulk of the papers dating from circa 1920 - circa 1970. The collection includes correspondence between Benn and his wife Velida de Benn and letters from Oscar Bluemner, Max Weber, Joseph Stella, and other artists. Also found are biographical materials, sketches, sketchbooks, diaries, scrapbooks, personal business records, clippings, photographs, exhibition catalogs, art journals, and auction catalogs. Some of the printed material is quite rare.
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence files dating from 1906 through 1993, and includes personal, professional, and family correspondence of Ben Benn and wife Velida Benn, as well as personal correspondence between the Benn's. Much of the professional correspondence relates to exhibitions and other projects and is with museums, galleries, and art associations, including the Whitney Museum of American Art, The Artists' Gallery, and the College Art Association. Additional correspondence contains letters from friends and colleagues including Alfred Barr, Oscar Bluemner, Rita Benton, Holger Cahill, Juliana Force, Sidney Geist, Kaj Klitgaard, Audrey McMahon, Julio Osma, Harry Salpeter, Hugh Stix, Hudson D. Walker, and Marguerite Zorach, among others. Letters exchanged between Ben Benn and Velida Benn primarily relate to Benn's activities in Woodstock, N.Y., Gloucester, Ma., and St. Augustine, Fla., places he visited during the early part of his career. Many of Benn's letters are illustrated. Velida Benn's correspondence includes letters from her brother Bernard Lopez, William M. Fisher (Metropolitan Museum of Art), Bessie Beatty, Rita Benton, Sidney Geist, and Julio Osma. Also found are brief notes from Joseph Stella, Max Weber, and Marsden Hartley.
Diaries (1943-1977) contain entries by Velida Benn and reflect her activities and personal observations; also found are numerous references to Benn's exhibitions and projects. Three scrapbooks (1915-1972) document Benn's exhibitions and include copies of correspondence, announcements, checklists, price lists, and clippings; many of the items are annotated. Artwork (1937-1974) consists of sketchbooks and various loose sketches of portraits, figures, and still lifes; also included are fashion sketches by Velida Benn.
Printed material (1905-1991, bulk 1930s-1970s) includes exhibition announcements and catalogs, newspaper and magazine clippings, printed programs, reproductions, and monographs. Of particular interest are Artists' and Writers' Chap Books (1933-1935) that include the work of Ben and Velida Benn. Photographs (1920-1969) contain images of works of art, of Ben Benn, individually and with Velida, and exhibition installation shots.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into seven series based primarily on type of material. Material within each series is arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1983, undated (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1906-1993, undated (Boxes 1-4; 4.0 linear ft.)
Series 3: Diaries, Notebooks, and Scrapbooks, 1915-1977, undated (Boxes 4-5; 11 folders)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, circa 1910-1979, undated (Box 5; 9 folders)
Series 5: Artwork, 1924-1974, undated (Box 5,7; 6 folders, 6 oversized items)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1911-1991, undated (Boxes 5-6; 2.0 linear ft.)
Series 7: Photographs and Negatives, 1920-1969, undated (Box 6; 6 folders)
Provenance
The Ben Benn papers were donated by Benn's nephew Peter Rosenberg to the Archives of American Art in 1988.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Artists' Gallery (New York, N.Y).; Benn, Velida; Bluemner, Oscar, 1867-1938; Force, Juliana, 1876-1948; Geist, Sidney; Harry Salpeter Gallery; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.).; Van Dine, S. S.; Walker Art Center.; Whitney Museum of American Art.; Illustrated letters; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, American--20th century; Painting, American--Economic aspects; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sketches
- Biographical Material, 1983, undated; Series 1; 2 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Two obituary notices of Ben Benn's death including the piece that ran in the New York Times, (1983). Also found is a copy of the entry on Benn published in Who's Who in American Art, 15th Edition.
  - Biographical Material, 1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1906-1993, undated; Series 2; 4 Linear feet Boxes 1-4
  This series contains the personal and professional correspondence of Ben Benn and personal correspondence of Velida Benn (neé Gertrude Lopez). Found are several letters from Willard Huntington Wright (the Forum Exhibition Committee) and Juliana Force (Whitney Museum of Art). Also included is correspondence from additional museums and galleries, including the Artists' Gallery, Brooklyn Museum, and the Metropolitan Museum of Art, among others. Personal correspondence includes numerous letters, postcards, and greeting cards from colleagues and friends who formed a part of the Benns' social circle, including those from Oscar Bluemner, Sidney Geist, and Kaj Klitgaard, William Baziotes, and a postcard from Marsden Hartley.
  Arrangement note
  The Correspondence series is arranged into five subseries:
  2.1: Ben Benn correspondence, 1915-1993, undated
  2.2: Ben and Velida Benn correspondence, 1911-1953, undated
  2.3: Velida Benn correspondence, 1906-1963, undated
  2.4: Postcards, 1910-1969, undated
  2.5: Greeting cards, 1918-1967, undated
  - Ben Benn Correspondence, 1915-1993, undated; 2.1
    Chronological professional and personal letters received by Ben Benn relating to exhibitions, affiliations with various artists' groups, and relationships with other artists and friends. Found are letters from Alfred Barr, Holger Cahill, Juliana Force, Sidney Geist, Kaj Klitgaard, Rowan and Irene LeCompte, Audrey McMahon, Elie and Viola Nadelman, Samuel Rosenblum, Harry Salpeter, and Hugh Stix, and various art galleries and museums, including the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Newark Museum, and the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, and the Walker Art Center Also found is correspondence from containing letters from Hudson Walker and others, relating to Benn's one-man exhibition; included are price lists of Benn's paintings.
    Appendix: Notable Correspondents from Series 2.1, Ben Benn Correspondence
    Abbott, Jere, (See The Museum of Modern Art)
    American Artists' Congress, 1936 (1 letter)
    American British Art Center, 1944 (1 letter
    American Federation of the Arts, 1959 (1 letter)
    American Society of Painters, Sculptors, and Gravers, 1935-1936 (3 letters)
    American Society for Technion, Women's Division, Israel Institute of Technology, 1958 (4 letters)
    Anderson Galleries, The, 1922 (2 letters)
    Arden Studios, Inc., 1931 (1 letter)
    Art Appreciation Movement, 1942
    Art For Living, 1949 (1 letter)
    Art USA, 1959 (2 letters)
    Artists Equity Association, 1951 (1 letter)
    Artists' Gallery, The, 1937-1956 (11 letters)
    Artists' and Sculptors' Division, Joint Distribution Committee, 1938 (1 letter)
    Artists for Victory, 1943 (1 letter)
    Artists Welfare Fund, Inc., 1973 (1 letter)
    Associated American Artists, 1942 (1 letter)
    Avery, Milton, 1930 (1 letter)
    Barr, Alfred A., 1953-1956 (2 letters): See also The Museum of Modern Art
    Baziotes, William, 1942 (1 letter)
    Beer-Monti, Federica, (See The Artists' Gallery)
    Bender, William H., 1968 (1 letter)
    Benton, Tom, undated (1 letter)
    Benton, Rita and Tom, 1925 (1 letter)
    Benton, Rita, 1926-1928, undated (2 letters)
    Biddle, George, 1949-1950 (3 letters)
    Bluemner, Oscar, 1918-1932 (2 letters)
    Blume, Peter, (See The National Institute of Arts and Letters)
    Board, Brewster, (See First Municipal Art Exhibition)
    Bourgeois Galleries, 1917-1918 (5 letters)
    Bourgeois, P., (See Bourgeois Galleries)
    Bourgeois, S., (See Bourgeois Galleries)
    Breckinridge, Mrs. Henry, (See City of New York, Municipal Art Committee)
    Brooklyn Museum, 1931-1932 (4 letters)
    Brown, George Lippincott, 1922 (1 letter)
    Brownell-Lamberston Galleries, 1930 (1 letter)
    Bruckel, Fred H., (See Montross Gallery)
    Bry, Edith, (See Artists' and Sculptors' Division, Joint Distribution Committee)
    Bummell, Peter, (See The Museum of Modern Art)
    Burck, Jacob, (See New Masses)
    Cahill, Holger, (See First Municipal Art Exhibition): See also Works Progress
    Administration/Federal Art Project
    Carmel, Hilda, (See Artists Welfare Fund)
    Chidsey, Alan C., 1937 (1 letter)
    City of New York, Municipal Art Committee, 1936 (3 letters)
    Coady, R.W., 1915-1918 (5 letters)
    Codry, Patrick, (See New Masses)
    Coffey, Katherine, (See The Newark Museum)
    Cohen, Mildred, (See College Art Association)
    College Art Association, 1932-1936 (5 letters; 1 press release)
    Committee of Five/League for American Citizenship, 1928 (1 letter)
    Corcoran Gallery of Art, The, 1938 (1 letter)
    Dasburg, Andrew, 1921, undated (2 letters)
    Educational Art Alliance, 1944 (1 letter)
    The Day, 1935 (1 letter)
    Egan, Charles, (See Egan Gallery)
    Egan Gallery, 1946 (1 letter)
    Elliott, James H., 1954 (1 letter)
    Fair Lawn Art Association, The, 1950 (1 letter)
    Ferargil Galleries, 1934 (1 letter)
    First Municipal Art Exhibition, 1934 (2 letters)
    Fisher, William, 1917-1925 (5 letters)
    Fitzgerald, Eleanor M., The Studio Theatre, 1941 (2 letters)
    Force, Juliana, (See Whitney Museum of American Art)
    Ford Foundation, The, 1958-1960 (7 letters)
    Forum Exhibition Committee, The, 1916 (6 letters)
    Fraser, Joseph T., (See The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts)
    Frueh, Mr. and Mrs. Alfred, 1916 (1 invitation)
    Frueh, Alfred, 1917 (1 invitation)
    Frueh, Giuliette, 1923 (1 letter)
    Geist, Sidney, 1939-1959 (35 letters)
    Gerdts, William H., (See The Newark Museum)
    Glassgold, C. Adolph, (See Whitney Museum of American Art)
    Goff, Carleton, (See Providence Art Club)
    Gollomb, Joseph, 1931, undated (2 letters)
    Goodyear, A. Conger, (See The Museum of Modern Art)
    Hale, Robert Beverly, (See The Metropolitan Museum of Art)
    Hamlin, Elizabeth, (See Brooklyn Museum)
    Hanna Ray, (See John Wanamaker New York)
    Harris, Ruth F., (See The New York Times)
    Hartley, Marsden, 1934 (1 postcard)
    Hellman, George, 1926-1927 (2 letters): See also The New Gallery
    Hirschhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1974 (1 letter)
    Horch, Louis L., (See Roerich Museum)
    Irvine, Rosalind, (See Whitney Museum of American Art)
    Johnston, E.M., (See Bourgeois Galleries)
    Katz, Harry, The Library of Congress, 1993 (1 letter)
    Kent, H.W., (See The Metropolitan Museum of Art)
    Klitgaard, Georgina and Kaj, 1920 (1 letter)
    Klitgaard, Kaj, 1921-1936, undated (8 letters)
    Korzenik, Lillian, (See American Society for Technion, Women's Division, Israel Institute of Technology
    Krasne, Bell, 1954-1955 (2 letters)
    Kruse, Alexander Z., 1941 (1 letter)
    Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, (See American Artists' Congress)
    LaGuardia, Fiorello, 1941 (1 letter)
    Lambertson, Dorothy, (See Brownell-Lambertson Galleries)
    Lang, Gladys V., (See The Metropolitan Museum of Art)
    Laurent, Robert, 1920 (1 letter)
    Lechay, James, 1971 (1 letter)
    LeCompte, Rowan, 1949-1953 (12 letters)
    LeCompte, Irene and Rowan, 1952-1967 (12 letters)
    LeCompte, Irene, 1951-1953 (4 letters)
    Lerner, Abram, (See Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden)
    Lewis, Robert, 1950-1952 (5 letters)
    Lowry, W. McNeill, (See The Ford Foundation)
    McBride, Henry, 1932 (1 letter)
    McCausland, Elizabeth, 1951 (1 letter)
    McKinney, Roland, (See Pepsi-Cola's Fifth Annual Art Competition): See also The Metropolitan Museum of Art
    McMahon, Audrey, (See College Art Association)
    Mallette, Alice, (See The Museum of Modern Art)
    Marantz, Evelyn, (See Art For Living)
    Marvel, Josiah P., The Springfield Museum of Art, 1932 (2 letters)
    Meeting Place, The, 1931, (2 letters)
    Metropolitan Museum of Art, The, 1939-1957 (8 letters)
    Miller, Ann, (See The Fair Lawn Art Association)
    Minnigerode, C. Powell, (See The Corcoran Gallery of Art)
    Montross Gallery, 1930 (1 letter)
    More, Hermon, (See Whitney Museum of American Art)
    Museum of Modern Art, The, 1931-1951, undated (5 letters)
    Musgrove, Louis, 1935-1954, undated (4 letters)
    Musgrove, Nonnie, 1963 (1 letter)
    Nadelman, Elie, 1915 (1 letter): in French
    Nadelman, Elie and Viola, 1921-1947, undated 6 letters)
    Nadelman, Viola, 1925-1929 (4 letters)
    National Society of American Art, 1934 (2 letters)
    Nestor, Bernard and Dudley Pratt, (See Seattle Art Museum)
    New Gallery, The, 1926-1927 (2 letters)
    New Masses, 1933 (3 letters)
    Newark Museum, The, 1958 (4 letters)
    New York Times, The, 1938-1957 (2 letters)
    Nordness, Lee, (See Art USA)
    Ostrowsky, Abbo, (See Educational Art Alliance)
    Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, The, 1942-1965 (3 letters)
    Pepsi-Cola's Fifth Annual Art Competition, 1948 (3 letters)
    Phillips Memorial Gallery, 1929 (1 letter)
    Providence Art Club, 1965 (3 letters)
    Rickey, George, 1936 (1 letter)
    Ritchie, Andrew C., (See The Museum of Modern Art)
    Robinson, Eleanor, (See Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.)
    Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., 1940 (1 letter)
    Roerich, Horch L., (See Roerich Museum)
    Roerich Museum, 1936 (1 letter)
    Rogovin, Howard, 1956 (4 letters)
    Rollins, Lloyd L., 1944 (3 letters): See also Works Progress Administration/Federal Art Project
    Ross, Sidney, (See Theatre in Art Exhibition)
    Rowan, Edward B., (See Treasury Department, Section of Painting and Sculpture)
    Saarinen, Aline B., (See The New York Times)
    Salpeter, Harry, (See Harry Salpeter Gallery, Inc.)
    Harry Salpeter Gallery, Inc., 1956-1961 (11 letters)
    Seattle Art Museum, 1933 (1 letter)
    Shahn, Ben, 1949 (1 letter)
    Slatkin, Charles E., (See Charles E. Slatkin Galleries)
    Charles E. Slatkin Galleries, Inc., 1959 (1 letter)
    Society of Independent Artists, The, 1923 (1 letter)
    Marie Sterner Fine Arts, 1930 (1 letter)
    Stix, Hugh, 1930-1960 (6 letters): See also The Artists' Gallery
    Theatre in Art Exhibition, 1932 (2 letters)
    Treasury Department, Section of Painting and Sculpture, 1934 (1 letter)
    Tschudy, Herbert B., (See Brooklyn Museum)
    Usher, Elizabeth, (See The Metropolitan Museum of Art)
    Van Deventer, S., Kröller-Müller Museum, 1924 (1 letter)
    Varian, Dorothy, 1937 (1 letter)
    Von Groschwitz, Gustave, (See Ferargil Galleries)
    Walker Art Center, 1953-1954 (17 letters)
    Walker, Hudson, 1948-1958 (6 letters): See also Hudson Walker Art Center
    Walkowitz, Abraham, 1928 (1 letter)
    John Wanamaker New York, 1934 (1 letter)
    Wehle, Harry B., (See The Metropolitan Museum of Art)
    Weichsel, John, The People's Guild, 1915 (1 letter)
    Whitney Museum of American Art (pre-1930: Whitney Studio Club), 1927-1950, undated (16 letters)
    Woodstock Artists Association, 1977 (1 letter)
    Works Progress Administration/Federal Art Project, 1935-1936 (2 letters)
    Wright, Willard Huntington, (See The Forum Exhibition Committee)
    Yiddisher Kultur Farband, 1951 (1 letter)
    Zorach, William, 1916 (1 letter)
    Appendix B: Notable Correspondents from Series 2.3: Velida Benn Correspondence, 1906-1963
    Art Foundation, The, 1943 (Page proof of advertisement for Art News)
    Ashton, Dore, The New York Times, 1958 (1 letter)
    Avery, Sally, 1934 (1 letter)
    Benton, Rita, 1925 (2 letters)
    Bluemner, Oscar, undated (1 letter)
    Bouché, Louis, 1918 (2 letters)
    Champanier, Abram, 1933 (1 letter)
    City of New York, The, Department of Parks, 1915 (Permit to paint and sketch in the boroughs of Manhattan and Richmond)
    Columbia University, 1928-1929 (4 letters)
    Force, Juliana, 1933 (1 letter)
    Freeman, Anne, (See Juliana Force)
    Furlong, Tomás, 1909-1911 (3 letters; 1 letter in Spanish)
    Geist, Sidney, 1941-1949 (14 letters)
    Hartley, Marsden, 1934 (1 postcard, surname omitted)
    Haskell, Juliana, (See Columbia University)
    Hitchings, Elisabeth J., College Art Association 1935 (1 letter)
    Kelly, Anne, (See Mrs. John D. Rockefeller)
    Klitgaard, Kaj, undated (1 note)
    LeCompte, Irene, 1951-1953, (2 letters)
    LeCompte, Rowan and Robert Lewis, 1949 (1 letter)
    Mora, Luis F., 1911 (1 letter in Spanish)
    Nadelman, Viola, 1942 (1 letter)
    Osma, Julio, 1923-1924 (4 letters: 2 letters in Spanish)
    Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., 1931 (1 letter)
    Rollins, Lloyd, 1944 (2 postcards)
    Salpeter, Betty and Harry, 1956 (1 letter)
    Salpeter, Harry, 1960 (1 postcard)
    Sanger, William, 1915 (1 letter)
    Stella, Joseph, 1918 (1 letter)
    Stieglitz, Alfred, 1925 (1 letter)
    Weber, Max, 1918 (1 letter)
    Weischel, Mr. and Mrs., 1915 (1 postcard)
    Zorach, Marguerite, 1915-1916 (2 letters)
    - Correspondence, 1915-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3-43)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
    - Undated Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - Loose Envelopes, 1916-1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ben Benn and Velida Benn Correspondence, 1911-1953, undated; 2.2
    Correspondence exchanged between Ben and Velida when Benn traveled to Woodstock, N.Y., Gloucester, Ma., and St. Augustine, Fla., as well as from Benn's studio in New York. Benn's letters focus on personal matters, various activities, and projects, and include references to colleagues and to the paintings he sold to various individuals. Many of the letters are illustrated. Velida Benn's letters relate to her activities and the New York art scene.
    - Correspondence, 1911-1934 (Box 2, Folder 19-42)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1937, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Undated Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
    - Loose Envelopes, 1923, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Velida Benn (Gertrude Lopez) Correspondence, 1906-1963, undated; 2.3
    This subseries, arranged chronologically, consists of letters received by Velida Benn from family, friends, and colleagues. Included are letters from Bessie Beatty, Rita Benton, William M. Fisher, Sidney Geist, Bernard Lopez, and Julio Osma. Also found are brief notes from Joseph Stella, Max Weber, and Marsden Hartley. Letters from Juliana Haskell relate to a Ben Benn one-man exhibition at Columbia University in 1928-1929. Included are numerous letters from publishers, theatrical agents, and producers to whom Velida Benn submitted her plays and poems.
    Please see Appendix B for list of notable correspondents.
    - Bernard Lopez Letters, 1906-1912, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - William M. Fisher Letters, 1912-1917, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-13)
    - Bessie Beatty Letters, 1942-1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 15-45)
    - Undated Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
    - Loose Envelopes, 1923-1944 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Postcards, 1910-1969, undated; 2.4
    This subseries is arranged chronologically and includes postcards to Ben and Velida Benn and Velida Benn from friends and colleagues. Postcards are from Hilton Kramer, Belle Krasne, Harry Salpeter, and others.
    - Postcards, 1910-1969 (Box 3, Folder 49-53)
    - Undated Postcards (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Greeting Cards, 1918-1967, undated; 2.5
    This subseries is arranged chronologically and includes holiday greeting cards received by Ben and Velida Benn from friends and colleagues.
    - Greeting Cards, 1918-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-17)
- Diaries, Notebooks, and Scrapbooks, 1915-1977, undated; Series 3; 11 Folders Boxes 4-5
  This series houses Velida Benn's diaries, notebook and notes, and Benn and Velida's scrapbooks. The diaries include references to Benn's activities, exhibitions and other projects, and the Benn family. Of interest are entries relating to Hilton Kramer, Seymour Hacker, and Hudson Walker, among others. The notebook and notes contain miscellaneous lists by Velida Benn. Three scrapbooks contain copies of correspondence, clippings, price lists, announcements, and parts of exhibition catalogs documenting Benn's museum and gallery shows from 1915 -1972. The arrangement of the scrapbooks has been retained in their original order.